<catalog>
    <game id="1">
        <name>Rain World</name>
        <image>resources/rainworld/icon.png</image>
        <description>
            Rain World is a 2017 survival-platform video game. It was released for PlayStation 4 and
            Microsoft Windows in March 2017 and Nintendo Switch in December 2018. The player
            controls a "slugcat" — an agile cat-like animal—that is tasked with survival in a
            derelict and hostile world. The slugcat traverses through the remnants of an
            industrialized ancient civilization as it searches for its family. It uses debris as
            weapons to escape from lethal predators, scavenge for food, and reach safe hibernation
            rooms before the deadly torrential rain arrives. Other game modes include multiplayer.
            Beginning in 2011, Rain World was in development for over six years by a two-man team
            and funded through Kickstarter, who intended to simulate a realistic ecosystem;
            creatures act independently of the player and perpetually wander through the
            environment. Rain World uses procedural animation and conveys much of its narrative
            through environmental storytelling, adopting an adaptive low-fi and electronic
            soundtrack. The player is given little explicit guidance so that they would feel like "a
            rat that lives on subway tracks", learning to survive in an environment without
            understanding its higher-level function.
        </description>
        <statistics>
            <developer>Videocult</developer>
            <publisher>Akupara Games</publisher>
            <year>2017</year>
            <score>94</score>
            <dlc>Yes</dlc>
        </statistics>
        <gallery>
            <image>resources/rainworld/screen1.png</image>
            <image>resources/rainworld/screen2.png</image>
            <image>resources/rainworld/screen3.png</image>
            <image>resources/rainworld/screen4.png</image>
            <image>resources/rainworld/screen5.png</image>
        </gallery>
    </game>
    <game id="2">
    </game>
    <game id="3">
    </game>
</catalog>