<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="HiH.xslt"?>
<catalog>
    <game id="1">
        <name>Rain World</name>
        <tags>Exploration Survival Indie</tags>
        <quote>
            "You're stuck in a cycle, a repeating pattern. You want a way out."
            <link source="https://rainworld.miraheze.org/wiki/Five_Pebbles/Dialogue#Survivor">Five Pebbles</link>
        </quote>
        <image source="resources/rainworld/icon.png"></image>
        <description>
            Rain World is a 2017 survival-platform video game. It was released for PlayStation 4 and
            Microsoft Windows in March 2017 and Nintendo Switch in December 2018. The player
            controls a "slugcat" — an agile cat-like animal—that is tasked with survival in a
            derelict and hostile world. The slugcat traverses through the remnants of an
            industrialized ancient civilization as it searches for its family. It uses debris as
            weapons to escape from lethal predators, scavenge for food, and reach safe hibernation
            rooms before the deadly torrential rain arrives. Other game modes include multiplayer.

            Beginning in 2011, Rain World was in development for over six years by a two-man team
            and funded through Kickstarter, who intended to simulate a realistic ecosystem;
            creatures act independently of the player and perpetually wander through the
            environment. Rain World uses procedural animation and conveys much of its narrative
            through environmental storytelling, adopting an adaptive low-fi and electronic
            soundtrack. The player is given little explicit guidance so that they would feel like "a
            rat that lives on subway tracks", learning to survive in an environment without
            understanding its higher-level function.
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rain_World">Quoted from the Wikipedia article.</link>
        </description>
        <characters>
            <character name="Artificer">
                <image source="resources/rainworld/Artificer.png">Image of Artificer</image>
            </character>
            <character name="Saint">
                <image source="resources/rainworld/Saint.png">Image of Saint</image>
            </character>
            <character name="Five Pebbles">
                <image source="resources/rainworld/Pebbles.png">Image of Five Pebbles</image>
            </character>
        </characters>
        <statistics>
            <developer>Videocult</developer>
            <publisher>Akupara Games</publisher>
            <date format="YYYY-MM-DD">2017-03-28</date>
            <score>94</score>
            <dlc>Yes</dlc>
            <dlcList>
                <title date="2023">Rain World: Downpour</title>
                <title date="2025">Rain World: The Watcher</title>
            </dlcList>
        </statistics>
        <gallery>
            <image source="resources/rainworld/screen1.png">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/rainworld/screen2.png">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/rainworld/screen3.png">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/rainworld/screen4.png">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/rainworld/screen5.png">Screenshot of the game</image>
        </gallery>
    </game>
    <game id="2">
        <name>Portal 2</name>
        <tags>Platformer Puzzle Story-Rich</tags>
        <quote>
            "Oh, hi. So, how are you holding up? Because I'm a potato!"
            <link source="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Portal_2#GLaDOS">GLaDOS</link>
        </quote>
        <image source="resources/rainworld/icon.png"></image>
        <description>
            Portal 2 is a 2011 puzzle-platform game developed by Valve for Windows, macOS, Linux, PlayStation 3, and Xbox 360. 
            The digital PC versions are distributed online by Valve's Steam service, 
            while all retail editions are distributed by Electronic Arts. A port for the Nintendo Switch was released 
            as part of the Portal: Companion Collection in June 2022.
                    
            Like the original Portal (2007), players solve puzzles by placing portals and teleporting between them. 
            Portal 2 adds features including tractor beams, lasers, light bridges, and paint-like gels that alter player movement or 
            allow portals to be placed on any surface. In the single-player campaign, players control Chell, who navigates the dilapidated 
            Aperture Science Enrichment Center during its reconstruction by the supercomputer GLaDOS (Ellen McLain); new characters 
            include robot Wheatley (Stephen Merchant) and Aperture founder Cave Johnson (J. K. Simmons). In the new cooperative mode, 
            players solve puzzles together as robots Atlas and P-Body (both voiced by Dee Bradley Baker). 
            Jonathan Coulton and the National produced songs for the game. 
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portal_2">Quoted from the Wikipedia article.</link>
        </description>
        <characters>
            <character name="GLaDOS">
                <image source="resources/portal2/GLaDOS.png">Image of GLaDOS</image>
            </character>
            <character name="Wheatley">
                <image source="resources/portal2/Wheatley.png">Image of Wheatley</image>
            </character>
        </characters>
        <statistics>
            <developer>Valve</developer>
            <publisher>Valve</publisher>
            <date format="YYYY-MM-DD">2011-04-18</date>
            <score>98</score>
            <dlc>No</dlc>
        </statistics>
        <gallery>
            <image source="resources/portal2/screen1.jpg">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/portal2/screen2.jpg">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/portal2/screen3.jpg">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/portal2/screen4.jpg">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/portal2/screen5.jpg">Screenshot of the game</image>
        </gallery>
    </game>
    <game id="3">
        <name>Risk of Rain 2</name>
        <tags>Roguelike Co-op Shooter</tags>
        <quote>
            "I am alive. My creators have scorned me, and imprisoned me in this realm for I am beautiful."
            <link source="https://riskofrain2.wiki.gg/wiki/Providence">Providence</link>
        </quote>
        <image source="resources/riskofrain/icon.png"></image>
        <description>
            Risk of Rain 2 is a roguelite third-person shooter developed by Hopoo Games and published by Gearbox
            Publishing. A sequel to 2013's Risk of Rain, it was released in early access for Microsoft Windows,
            Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 4, and Xbox One in 2019 before fully releasing in August 2020 with a
            release for Stadia coming a month later. Versions for PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S released in August 2024.

            Players control a survivor who is stranded on an alien planet. To survive, they navigate
            through various environments, killing monsters and looting chests to collect items that boost
            their offensive and defensive capabilities. Over time, the game's difficulty increases,
            spawning more powerful and dangerous creatures. The game supports up to four players in online
            multiplayer. The game received generally positive reviews upon release. There are many characters, each
            one having a different way to play.
            <link source="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Risk_of_Rain_2">Quoted from the Wikipedia article.</link>
        </description>
        <characters>
            <character name="Captain">
                <image source="resources/riskofrain/Captain.png"></image>
            </character>
            <character name="Mercenary">
                <image source="resources/riskofrain/Saint.png"></image>
            </character>
            <character name="Engineer">
                <image source="resources/riskofrain/Engineer.png"></image>
            </character>
            <character name="Railgunner">
                <image source="resources/riskofrain/Railgunner.png"></image>
            </character>
        </characters>
        <statistics>
            <developer>Hopoo Games</developer>
            <publisher>Gearbox Publishing</publisher>
            <date format="YYYY-MM-DD">2020-08-11</date>
            <score>94</score>
            <dlc>Yes</dlc>
            <dlcList>
                <title date="2022">Risk of Rain 2: Survivors of the Void</title>
                <title date="2024">Risk of Rain 2: Seekers of the Storm</title>
                <title date="2025">Risk of Rain 2: Alloyed Collective</title>
            </dlcList>
        </statistics>
        <gallery>
            <image source="resources/riskofrain/screen1.png">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/riskofrain/screen2.png">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/riskofrain/screen3.png">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/riskofrain/screen4.png">Screenshot of the game</image>
            <image source="resources/riskofrain/screen5.png">Screenshot of the game</image>
        </gallery>
    </game>
</catalog>